Never forget why you are the church.
Listen, guys, what a wonderful morning.
While you're turning your Bibles, really, we have
a lot of places to turn, so what I'm going to do is just turn,
just open your Bible, and we're going to be everywhere.
How's that sound?
We're in a series that is pretty gonna,
you know, just take us a lot of places.
I do want to say this.
I want to make a welcome.
Pastor Ryan, I'm going to blow your cover, you know what I'm saying?
And his wife, Amy, he is lead pastor of Crossroads
Fellowship, over by Tucker Crossroads, doing a great and phenomenal
job out there, very giving and mission minded church.
So we're glad to have him.
A little interesting note about Ryan.
He was one of the only people in my life.
The only people in my life to hire me, and then fire me.
Yeah, boy.
He's here.
Anyway.
Been waiting for this for years.
Today is the day, Ryan.
But no, listen, it was funny.
So he was a manager at American Jewel, and I
worked there for a little bit and it was so it was
hilarious because I'd never been fired from a job before.
And, uh, and since still haven't since then.
So don't get no ideas, but, um,
But I go into the 90 day meeting, you know what I'm saying?
Like the, and man, I've already told, you know, all the people I know and and
Heather and my family, I'm going,
I'm asking for a raise, you know what I'm saying?
I want to get paid well and all stuff.
And before I could even get that, he said, yeah, we're not retaining you.
Ain't that just a blessing?
But regardless of all that, it is amazing to see where God has brought us.
Amen.
And so that's all jokes aside, I'm glad he's
on vacation, and so it is an honor and privilege for him to choose
to be here with his wife, Amy.
And so, um, I don't take that for granted, okay?
And by the way, pastors need breaks too.
Amen.
And so I'm glad he's getting one.
But after one week, a one week break from our series of core
values here at Cedar Grove.
We come to the 4th one.
Remember, last week was harvest day.
And so we were talking about the parable
that Jesus taught about going out in a vineyard and working and
getting paid, what we have agreed on and all the things.
And I want to make something clear this morning as we continue
this series of our core values.
If you are a guest, and maybe you're pondering and becoming a member here at Cedar Grove.
I want you to consider this series, your new
membership your new covenant membership class, okay?
We don't have one of those.
We'd love to have one of those, but if you want to know what we're about, you
want to know why we are, who we are, and where we gather, this
is a great series for you to just really lash your teeth on, and
understand all that.
This series is also made to renew the understanding of
what it means to be a member here of this local church.
Just to quickly remind us this morning, our vision, Cedar
Grow Baptist Church exists to create a space where people and
families can meet Jesus, find community and grow in their faith.
Our mission is our purpose is to love others unconditionally,
learn about God increasingly.
Live to share Jesus intentionally and lead others to Christ continually,
in Lebanon, Tennessee throughout the whole world.
So we see that our mission is how we get to our vision.
But here's the issue.
Neither of these statements will matter if we do not
value the right things in the right way.
What you value in life, we'll direct your life.
And you can see that in every single aspect of your life.
Before you knew Christ,
You were literally bound by the lust of the flesh,
the lust of the eyes, the pride of life, and that's what directed you.
You value the satisfaction in the flesh, therefore
you lived according to it.
But then Jesus comes in.
Amen.
You meet them.
And he changes everything.
Now we think differently.
Our minds have been transformed by the renewing of
our minds.
So we are looking at these core values in
the form of statements of agreement for each one.
The 1st one.
We talked about.
I will uphold the sanctity of the family.
Family is our first core value.
Our families can either be something that brings us closer to God or further from God.
Listen, God did not bless us with a family to set them up as idols in our life.
Notice how it gets quiet right there.
You know why?
Because so often what we do is we say, Jesus, family, church,
but in reality, the way we live our lives, the way we
are directed, what we value, it's family, Jesus, and everything else.
Guys, that's not gonna work.
He desires the family to be a place of holiness and faith building.
Listen, if you don't make your family first, don't expect your family to make
him, or if you don't make Jesus first, don't expect your family to make him first.
So I will uphold the sanctity of the family.
The 2nd one, I will live daily with integrity in
thought, word, and deed.
To live honestly before God and others is the only way to back up
a beautiful testimony of the change God has made
in your life.
Listen, do you know, if you've hung out with me outside a pulpit,
you realize, I hope you realize that I try to be the same person
away from this pulpit that I am in this pulpit.
If I can't be, there's a problem.
I mean, I can't make it any simpler than that, right?
Now, you can think that I'm rough around the edges.
People sit there.
I cannot tell you.
I mean, times would say, hold on, did you say you were a pastor?
Yes, I'm a pastor, right?
But that also means I'm a human.
I'm not going to sit around in a suit and tie all day long doing this
and just, you know, listen, hey, I'm living life like y'all are with
y'all for the glory of God.
Amen.
So listen, right here, we had to live honestly, not just in front of
people, but also privately.
The 3rd, when I were building, grow each of the 4 relationships
represented in the purpose statement of my church.
Our mission statement speaks the 3 main relationships that we
all have, whether stewarded well or not.
Our relationship with others, our relationship with God and His Word,
our relationship with the mission.
This morning, we continue right along with our 4th core value.
By the way, if you missed any of those, you can go online, you can catch up.
Joe does a great job with our media player, our app, and our website, and everything.
You can, I mean, I'm talking, like, go and do that, okay?
Take advantage of it.
Amen?
But the 4th core value that we're going to talk about this morning is very simple commitment.
Commitment.
Without commitment, it is difficult to have a thriving ministry of any kind.
You got to have people that are committed.
I always say this, people, and I'll say
this because I've heard it a lot over and over and
over from many people and from many years of ministry,
but hey, we'll just do whatever God tells us to do.
Well go wherever God tells us.
That's fine, but wherever you are, be 10 toes down.
Be committed.
I'm telling you right now, God could call me away tomorrow, but guess what?
I'm planning on being here the rest of my life.
So until he does, guess what?
I'm here.
And I don't have to continuously say that we're just here.
We're committed, right?
Our statement of agreement is this.
I will wholeheartedly commit myself to
the purpose and mission of my church.
I will wholeheartedly commit myself to the purpose and mission of my church.
Now, I need everyone to say, I'm with you.
Because we're gonna go into this.
We're going to talk about things that modern society and culture
has made awkward to talk about because no one wants to talk about it because we struggle with it.
And I just need you to know, if there's a holy hush, there's a holy hush.
But I'm preaching this thinking message.
You got me?
Amen?
And if you get mad, you get mad at me.
Preaching?
Yeah, Philip.
Preach it.
If you can get mad, you can.
You can get mad.
And if you're a guest, you might be thinking, man, I'm out of here.
I'm never listen, hey, don't do that.
I want God to speak to us through his word, even if it hurts.
Okay?
Let's pray.
Father, I thank you, Lord, for your word.
God, I pray you give me power, liberty, and clarity to preach your word, God.
God, I pray you soften our hearts, God, so you can pierce our hearts, God,
for your glory, God.
God, I pray respond in such a way as honoring to you.
God, I pray that we are shaped by your word this morning.
God, is anyone who is here who is lost.
God, I pray through the understanding and the conviction of
the Holy Spirit, the fact that Jesus lived, died, and rose again,
ascended into heaven, and is going to return soon and very soon.
God, I pray they are saved in Jesus' name.
God, we thank you.
We love us in Jesus' name, pray.
And but he said, Amen.
Again, I will wholeheartedly commit myself to the purpose and mission of my church.
If there's anything missing from the church today, it is this.
People being committed to the purpose in the mission.
There is a stat that I cannot stand to hear, but when looked at closely,
it is sadly accurate for many churches.
10% of the people of a local church do 90%
of all the work that goes on.
Now, with that being said, I do want to encourage you today, I
do believe that we are seeing a shift in the culture here at Cedar Grove.
I believe that we have such an amount of people that
want to serve God, that want to glorify him, that
want to do the mission, love, learn, live, live.
But I'm telling you right now, there are still people that are on the fringe.
Although there's more help needed, we do have a good group of people that desire
to help and see the ministry and gospel impact grow,
we should not ever take that for granted.
What about those in the sidelines?
There are many who are content with letting someone else do it.
There are many who do not have any commitment to the purpose and mission
of the church coming on Sunday.
Listen, is simply not enough.
Guys, listen, if I just came on Sunday with no prep Monday through Saturday,
we wouldn't have what we have with the word.
We'd have the word, but I'd be a babbling mess.
The impact would be hindered because of a lack of preparation.
Coming to big events is simply not enough.
Those are results of the commitment of others who work hard to
make sure we have a ministry of excellence here.
I told you, these people who are content on the sidelines of what I would call the fringe.
By the way, if you are uncomfortable right now already and feel like I'm speaking
to you, I need you to hear me with all the love in my heart, I am.
If what I am saying is making you uncomfortable, then get off the sidelines.
The whole point of this core value is to get you from the fringe to the fold.
There's three ways for this to happen, three ways that we show our commitment to
the purpose and mission of the church first, we show that commitment
by attending faithfully.
How do you value the corporate gathering of believers?
See, God makes it clear that it should be a priority, and you
know the scripture I'm going to, but it's right there in Hebrews 10:25,
not forsaking the assembling of ourselves together as the manner of
some is, but exhorting one another.
And so much the more as you see the day approaching.
That word manner literally means in that scripture, custom,
practice, and habit.
Listen, what we're not talking about here is missing on going
on vacation once a year, twice a year.
being sick and not being able to come.
We're not talking about just the random times you can't attend.
We're talking about a habitual neglecting of the corporate gathering.
You know what breaks my heart when people do not understand how important the family of God is?
I hear people all the time say things like this.
Well, preacher, you know it's travel ball season.
We make it when we can.
Well, you know, it's hunting season.
I'll be in the woods with God, most of the several next several months,
well, you better be coming out like a renewed saint.
Amen?
Coming in ready to go straight to nursery.
That typically don't happen, no.
Well, we just got a lot going on right now.
Who don't?
That's life.
That's what makes this even more special.
Remember those hands that went up?
Difficult circumstances all around the place, but yet we're together today.
Mm.
We got family coming in.
I hear that all the time.
Well, bring them to church.
Preacher, this...
Preacher, this never happens.
But I overslept.
Liar.
You always sleep all the time.
It don't matter how late we make sure.
You'd be late for a Monday night service, amen?
But either way, again, I want to understand something this morning.
Do not hear what I'm not saying.
It is not a sin to miss church every now and again.
It's not a sin when you have simply something that you have
to do or have to handle.
There's people that have to work on Sunday in order to put food on the table.
We are not shaming them this morning.
That's not the that's why we work so hard to be able to
get what we're doing here out there.
So that's not what we're saying, but things do happen,
sports, activities, hunting, family, it's
all okay in their proper place.
These things become a problem when they become a, when they create
a habit of neglecting the gathering of
the saints, this goes beyond Sunday morning, you do realize,
we just talked about it.
Life groups, Sunday school Sunday morning at 9.15,
you say, well, that's just too early for us to make it.
It's difficult to get everyone ready and on time, then prioritize it better in the home.
Oh.
So that's what's going to get you this morning.
What I'm trying to say is this.
If we had an event or a ball game or a practice or
we had something that we had to go to, guess what we do?
d be there.
What we value dictates our decisions.
Y'all would be saying, amen.
That's good, that's good.
You say, well, I just, uh, you know, I'm not a fan of how they teach.
Okay.
Let's talk about it.
You can start a group and start teaching.
I mean, I'm just being honest with you, guys.
Listen, hey, again, this is just practical biblical teaching right here.
This is just understanding.
Listen, sometimes we over, we try to over spiritualize
things to hide behind that spirituality.
Understand that walking with Christ is as practical as it gets.
It's each and every step.
How do we go from a lack of commitment to faithfully attending church?
Well, listen, all we got to do is understand why we're even here.
Look at the buildup of our scripture here in Hebrews 10 and verse 23.
It says, let us hold fast the profession of our faith without
wavering, for he is faithful, that promised,
and let us consider one another, to provoke unto
love and to good works.
Guys, you realize then it says, not forsaking the assembling
of ourselves together as a manner of some is, but
exhorting one another in so much the more as you see the day approaching.
Listen, when you look at church attendance in the reality that
your presence encourages, uplifts, and
provokes others to keep doing good, that's when everything changes.
Our faithful attendance is a result of considering each other.
I want you to know something.
We talk about the back row, right?
The more experienced ladies and gentlemen
in our church.
I'm not going to say old, but that's what more experience means.
Amen?
Listen, hey, there's times like Miss Margie right here, there's times to
where they can't be here just because they can't be here.
But you know what?
When they walk in, it brightens my smile.
When I'm able to go over there and give them a big hug, listen,
I don't care what's going on in my life.
It helps me.
I can tell you right now, listen, Miss Donna, if you don't know, Miss Donna's a prayer warrior.
And there has been times, and I say this specifically, because it's so specific.
I am not saying the others aren't.
I'm saying Ms. Donna, on multiple occasions, has come up
to me, and I've come down her, and I've given her a hug, and
she says, I just want you to know that I've prayed for you this morning.
She did not realize it, although I believe she did through the Holy Spirit,
that I needed that prayer, because I was struggling that morning, guess what she did?
She provoked me into good works.
Isn't God's word amazing?
It just comes to life.
It's just real.
See, listen, hey, when you think that church attendance is about you, I wouldn't be here either.
But when you realize it's about us, glorifying him?
Oh, that's a whole nother story.
Our faithful attendance is only one part, though.
I will wholeheartedly commit myself to the purpose and mission of my church by
giving cheerfully.
This is one of the most overly debated and controversial practices in the church today.
Should I give?
How much do I give?
Why do I even give?
Is tithing biblical?
And I can tell you this.
If a stance that you take, You
have to find every loophole not to act, What
you're doing is looking for a way not to, rather
than to glorify God in your actions.
Are y'all with me?
Anyone got children, they do it all the time.
Hey, go clean your room.
They will they will think I'm talking about, you don't think a
6 and 4 year old has a brain structure as good as they do, but
they come up with all the craziest reasons of why they just simply can't.
Oh, hope, Daddy, my my skeleton's broken.
Well, baby, you're doing pretty good for a broken skeleton.
I know God is good.
I mean, it's crazy.
Right?
Listen, it's a miracle.
We get done, and all of a sudden, how you want to go play outside?
Yeah, let's go.
What just happened?
Oh, I'm healed.
Listen, we will make all these
excuses on why we shouldn't do things.
Let's just go down to the nitty gritty here.
First off, it is important to understand that the principle of the time
predates the law, the principle of the time,
not the commandment of the time.
I need us to understand what I'm saying here.
I do not believe a tithe is commanded.
I do believe it's a good principle to follow in the New Testament church.
Both Abraham and Jacob 100s of years before the Mosaic
law was given, decided to
give a 10th of their possessions to the Lord.
This was tangible material possessions.
So it's not that it is mandated to the New Testament church to give a percentage.
However, not giving is simply not an option.
Also, a tithe is a good way to prioritize God first in your life.
I'm just going to be honest with you.
That's just practicality from the experience that I have in my life serving and giving a tie.
Listen, you know what?
It's amazing to me.
And people say this all the time, and I don't want to overspiritualize this.
It's amazing to me when the maths simply don't math, God works it out.
You don't think as a pastor that I have been, you know, tempted
every now and again to think, man, if I didn't give that, I could do
this, I could pay off that, I could do all these things.
You know, but no, God has provided in such a way that I'm able to give.
In the culture we live in, where our money goes there, there goes our heart.
As a matter of fact, this is the truth that has been around for a long time in a Sermon on the Mount.
Jesus says this in Matthew 6:21.
I told you we'd be everywhere.
If you're trying to follow good luck, okay?
All right?
Because what's gonna happen is we're gonna have to wait, and then we're gonna have to wait, and I'm just gonna tell you.
Matthew 6, 21, for where your treasure is, there will your heart be also.
So where do we give?
If we follow the practice in the Old Testament, we are to give to the storehouse, right?
A lot of people bring this as a commandment of the tithe.
Again, I believe in the principle of tithe, but Malachi 3.10, bring the
whole tithe into the storehouse.
So there may be food in my house and test me now in this, says the
Lord of hosts, if I will not open for you the windows of heaven and pour out for you a
blessing until it overflows.
A giving church is a thriving church.
You know what impresses me about certain ministries?
They're complete generosity no matter what.
God has blessed him in such a way that the people that church is
such givers, such generous, such cheerful, that when
a knee comes up, when a mission comes up, guess what they do?
They can give, why?
have to worry about it.
That's a thriving church.
Listen, when we give generously and intentionally, we lift the burden of financial
limitations on magnifying the ministry of this local church, and
in doing so, we lift up the name of Jesus.
Two options here.
If you think like this, you're tied.
By the way, we see here that your tithe goes to the church.
Well, I don't like how they spend the money where I go.
Okay, you have two options.
A, change your heart posture from pride to humulate.
Be humble.
Such a serious moment.
Let's try it again.
Hey, change your heart posture from pride to humility.
I can't say that word right now.
B, here's the thing.
stay with me.
B.
Leave that church and go somewhere you feel comfortable giving.
If you're in a church where you can't trust how they use the funds, why are you there?
Giving to external ministries is fine, but it's not given to the storehouse.
If you're outside given to charities or other ministries, with places you're
giving to the local church, you are hindering the ministry that you are supposed
to be committed to.
Is this just an Old Testament principle?
No.
Acts 4, 34, 37, neither was there any among them that lacked.
For as many as were possessors of lands or houses, sold them and
brought the prices of things that were sold and laid them down at the apostles' feet,
and distribution was made in every man according as he had need.
And Joseph, who by the apostles were surnamed Barnabas,
which is being interpreted as son of consolation, a Levite,
and of the country of Cyprus, having land sold it, and brought the money, and
laid it at the apostles' feet.
Now, listen, I need you to understand something.
None of that was commanded.
When Ananias and Sapphara came in, and what did he ask,
hey, when it was not in your possession, was it not yours?
But you've chosen to lie about it.
What I'm trying to say is, we read that, and I know some preachers can preach.
Oh, well, there you go.
Everyone should give as much and no, no, no, no.
There are certain people that have the gift of giving, that God has put in their heart, to give in abundance.
And there's certain people that give, that give, just out of what they've been
profited and what God has blessed them in.
Listen, whether it's little, whether it's much, whether it's a
whole bunch or very God can use it.
He just wants your heart.
I remember, I think the 1st time check that I gave was like $27.
But I was glad to give it.
This is not a call to sell your possessions, let doorstep of the church.
It's the call to give faithfully to the ministry effort that you were committed to.
And we do so cheerfully.
2 Corinthians 9 verse 7, each one must do just as he purposed in
his heart, not grudgingly or under compulsion, for God
loves a cheerful giver.
This is not allowing for someone not to give, rather, Paul is revealing how
we ought to give compared to how our heart posture should not be.
Are you happy to get to this church in order to see the name of Jesus spread more in a community?
If not, why?
I want to share a sobering reality here at Cedar Grove.
And everyone buckle up.
listen, hey, there's no good time to preach this.
Okay?
I know we got a lot of guests this morning, and I love you,
and I'm glad that you haven't left yet.
Amen.
But I want you to know we'll get past this core values, and it's good
because you know what we're about here.
We'll get back to Romans at some point.
We got about 3 more years in there, so we'll get there.
But I want to share a sobering reality here at Cedar Grove, because I believe God
is blessing us abundantly.
I just want you to know something.
Listen, the changes and the shifts
that we have seen in the last two to three years is incredible.
I have talked to pastor after pastor.
I've talked to ministry leader after ministry leader of other places, and
I just, they know my heart.
I've been sharing, I call for counsel, I call for wisdom and advice.
And I tell them what's going on, and they say, Listen, when I'm complaining, you know what they say?
Jacob, your church, that you pastor, has
gone through a 25 year life cycle, and three.
Guys, that's a blessing.
I mean, we're seeing, we're almost in a top 10% of
churches in baptism.
That's a blessing.
God is blessing us.
Listen, that's not about us.
It's about Jesus.
But man, it's good to be a part of.
But again, this sober reality, there are no names on my part attached
to these numbers as a pastor.
I cannot allow any temptation to care about someone more than another based on giving.
I've had people tell me, well, you know, if I leave, my child goes with me.
What you want me to tell you, brother?
Got to replace it.
And guess what he did?
He did.
Okay?
I mean, I'm not, we're not gonna test God in that way.
Amen?
But the last 6 months, we average 16, 18 givers a week.
I told you, it's gonna be sobering.
16, 18 givers a week.
This is considering all modes of giving on an average.
Our average Sunday attendance during this time has been 150 to 165.
Now, listen to me.
How much are we hindering the progress of the magnification,
the name of Jesus, by our lack of cheerful and faithful giving?
Our giving or lack of does nothing for his glory.
In other words, he is worthy of it all regardless.
He is totally capable, regardless.
Well, God doesn't need money to get things done.
You don't think that way about anything else in your life.
Stop hiding behind sp spiritualism.
Y'all still with me saying, man.
Amen.
Even the pastors went...
Woo!
Now, I do want to encourage.
On May 17th, we had our vision Sunday.
Every remember that?
If you were here, say, Amen.
If you weren't men, it was an awesome day.
I hope you're there next year.
But the yearly vision offering is what paid for the chairs that
you're sitting in, and the tables that you sat at on Sunday,
and the chairs that you sat in to eat in, and all the things, the
vision Sunday offerings, what built the pavilion that we were able to partake in.
I mean, there's a lot of things that have happened.
On that Sunday, on May 17th,
Listen to me now.
We had 35 givers give, not
including online or cash or anything like that.
That's just that's just strictly those kind of games.
We totaled over $21,000.
Listen to me.
That is over 4 times the amount of our weekly need right now.
And you know what was beautiful about that giving?
There was an evident anticipation and excitement of what God was going to do with it.
Y'all still with me?
Imagine if we came in every Sunday like that.
Nowhere in scripture will you find a given amount required just a giving heart required.
As a matter of fact, Paul uses the measurement of, as he may
prosper, what does that mean?
As God prospers you, you give accordingly, and in doing so, you
prosper the gospel ministry of that local church.
I want to say something else, just as a warning and statement of caution here.
In the culture that we live in, it has become popular to use online
platforms and followers, a ministry without ever having
to give or serve or think about anything other than getting fed.
I'm talking about YouTube, podcast, all these, all these
big names that are great.
Listen, I love live free.
I love deeper podcast.
I love the I love all these podcasts.
I listen to them on a weekly basis.
However, let's not forget those platforms
were started if not maintained by
the generous giving of that local church.
and how many people are being touched by it.
Let's not forget how powerful, cheerful, and generous giving is.
Now, I will wholeheartedly commit myself to the purpose and
mission of the church by attending faithfully, giving cheerfully but also by working diligently.
You realize anything worth having requires hard work and discipline.
King Solomon, the wisest and richest person in history, wrote this about hard work.
Proverbs 13, 4, the soul of a lazy man desires and has nothing, but
the soul, the diligence, shall be made rich.
God forbid we work hard everywhere else in our life except the house of God.
God forbid laziness being an issue here at Cedar Grove.
This brings up a constant that needs to be understood.
A lot of people have the mindset of maybe they tied their time.
And listen, before I go any further,
I get where you come from there.
It does it not make sense.
However, when we conflate the spiritual gifts
of helps and service that are legitimate and real grace
gifts, with the practice of generous and cheerful giving,
we've lost a deeper meaning of the two.
They work together, but they are not the same.
Now, again, I don't want to miss what Solomon is saying here.
People take this proverb and connect it only to getting rich in money or material things.
Let's look at that verse again.
Proverbs 13, verse 4.
The soul.
Everyone say soul.
of a lazy man desires and has nothing, but the soul of the diligent
man or the diligence shall be made rich.
What does that word sole mean?
Well, it means soul, living being, life, self person,
desire, appetite, emotion, passion.
To put this simply, the soul encompasses the whole person.
Physical, moral, and spiritual dimensions, not just
material circumstances.
In other words, we know that when we are diligent in our work,
It helps everything about us.
Our labor and our work for the Lord is never in vain.
Let's be honest with each other.
If you've been working in the ministry, you've done ministry.
There are times, in ministry, there are times walking with the
Lord that you think all you're doing for Jesus is in vain.
If it's just me, maybe you should work a little bit more.
Amen?
Because I tell you right now, there's times to where I get done preaching.
There's times to where I get done having a meeting or doing this,
doing that, and I look up and I think, God, is this even working?
What is, does any of this count?
Is there any progress?
It just seems like it's negative, after negative,
after tension, after conflict, after tension, after conflict,
But then I look at scripture.
I want you to understand, my feelings do not matter in the light of scripture.
Because the truth is this.
Therefore, my beloved, 1st Corinthians 1558, be
steadfast, immovable, always
abounding in the work of the Lord, knowing, not
hoping, not thinking, knowing that
your labor is not in vain, in the Lord.
Do you want more people to come to know Jesus through your effort and work?
I do.
Now, there's a balance.
Listen to me now.
There's a balance.
There's a whole nother message I can preach right here.
Don't get so busy that you miss Jesus.
Jesus is the reason why we're busy, but if we get busy and
ignore him, then we're, that's not the work of the Lord.
The work and the labor that we do has to be founded upon a personal relationship with him.
Proverbs 16, verse 3, commit your works to the Lord and your plans will be established.
When we were committed to the purpose and mission of the church.
We will attend faithfully, give cheerfully and work diligently.
What will the result be?
Anyone like me, and you like results.
Y'all weird people.
Like, y'all like results?
Yep.
One person had a whole big old crowd.
When I do something, there's a reason why I love mowing.
I love, love, love, mowing the yard.
I don't know why.
I got a little smaller yard, I hate more in my yard.
I hate it.
I like my neighbor's yard in my parents' yard.
You know what I'm saying?
Wow, my parents' yard, I get the, it's vast.
It's huge.
Man, it's a beautiful view.
There's work to be done, but as I'm doing it, I'm
feeding myself, you know, the podcast that
we're just talking about worship music, maybe a little fantasy football.
But either way, like, you know, I'm making sure that I'm getting refreshed in the Lord, right?
And then before you know it, the work is done and I get off the mower, put
the weeder down or get done with the blowing, I look, and I see the
result of the finished work.
Ain't nothing like it.
I even smell the result of the finished work.
You understand what I'm saying?
Like it hits every sense that I have.
And I like that.
Ministry can be the same way.
The result may not look like what you want it to look like.
But your labor is not in vain in the Lord.
Foolish, uh, foolish Pastor Jacob back in the day.
That's me.
A little foolish sometimes, I guess, now, too.
I don't know.
I said something when I took this church.
I said, We're not running, 300 people.
In five years, I quit.
Well, unless you're an evangelist, we don't have 300 people here.
But you know what we do have?
You've got people that love Jesus.
You've got testimony after testimony after testimony of people that
we're far from him, but now are near to him.
We've got marriages that have been restored.
We've got people that have been healed.
We've got kiddos that are learning the gospel.
We're baptizing kid after kid after kid.
Why?
Because we have a gospel driven children's program.
Our labor is not in vain.
We may not blow up to be the biggest church in Wilson County.
That dream is long gone.
But Gods, we can glorify Jesus.
So will you be committed?
Will you attend faithfully?
Will you give cheerfully?
Will you work diligently?
And let's do so together.
Heads bound eyes closed over this place.